Guide to the John Charles Denham Album of Watercolors and Drawings
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Denham Album, 1777-1856; Series I; 1 bound volume
  - Francia, François Louis Thomas: brown wash drawing of a beached ship (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Loutherbourg, Philippe-Jacques de: pen and ink wash drawing of a landscape, annotated with color considerations (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - Cosway, Richard: "Maria Cosway," graphite (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Pyne, W. H. (William Henry): "Smithfield Cattle Market," pen and ink wash (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Unidentified artist: ink wash drawing of three men (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Clennell, Luke: pen and ink wash drawing of a sportsman and dog (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Hearne, Thomas: "One of the churches at Coventry probably St. Michael's," graphite and ink wash (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Wright, John Massey: "The Monk," watercolor (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Unidentified artist, after Theodore Edward Hook: portrait of Theodore Hook, lithograph (Box 1, Folder 96 v)
  - Hook, Theodore Edward: letter to John Charles Denham, with a self-portrait of Hook describing his bad knee (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Batty, Robert: "A Candidate for Immortality/Scene in the Lütschine Thal," watercolor, 1827 (Box 1, Folder 97 v)
- Related Documents, 1935; Series II; 2
  Scope and Contents
  The series consists of two folders holding documents related to the Denham collection.
  - "Catalogue of Contents of Album collected by Mrs. C. Denham," small bound volume, author unknown, undated (Box 1)
    Inscribed on free front endpaper: The Property of Frank Tetley, Rosemount, North Hill Road, Headingly, Leeds. A carte-de-visite photograph of a painted portrait of Catherine Denham (Sawyer & Bird of Norwich and London, photographer) is laid in.
  - Memorandum by Frederick Beetham, the Red House, Knaresborough, written for Sir Harold Vincent Mackintosh, with notes about Beetham's ancestors in the Copeman family who had owned the album; autograph manuscript with a typed transcription, 1935 Jan 26 (Box 1)